<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<container xmlns="https://open.law/schemas/library" xmlns:cache="https://open.law/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://open.law/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://open.law/schemas/macro" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns:codified="https://open.law/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://open.law/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="Saint Regis Mohawk Tribal Code of Law">
  <prefix>Title</prefix>
  <num>4</num>
  <heading>Health, Safety and Welfare</heading>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>4.02</num>
    <heading>Fire Prevention and Building Code</heading>
    <annotations>
      <annotation type="Commentary">The Tribal Council has adopted ,as its own tribal law, the <a href="https://dos.ny.gov/laws-and-regulations-division-building-standards-and-codes">New York State Fire Prevention and Building Code</a>.</annotation>
    </annotations>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>4.03</num>
    <heading>Food Code</heading>
    <annotations>
      <annotation type="Commentary">The Tribal Council has adopted ,as its own tribal law, the United States Food and Drug Administration <a href="https://www.fda.gov/food/retail-food-protection/fda-food-code">Food Code</a>.</annotation>
    </annotations>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>4.04</num>
    <heading>Alcohol Beverages Control</heading>
    <container>
      <prefix>Subchapter</prefix>
      <num path-omit="true">1</num>
      <heading>Alcohol Beverages Control Act</heading>
      <text>This Ordinance shall be cited as the "St. Regis Mohawk Tribal Alcoholic Beverages Control Act" and, pursuant to the inherent sovereignty of the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Tribe of the State of New York, shall be deemed an exercise of the Tribe's powers for the purpose of protecting the welfare, health, peace, morals and safety of all people residing on the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Reservation of the State of New York.</text>
      <text>All of the provisions of this Ordinance shall be liberally construed to accomplish the above declared purpose. It is the St. Regis Mohawk Tribe's declared intent in enacting this Ordinance to regulate and control all traffic in liquor on the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Reservation of the State of New York except to the extent allowed and permitted under the express terms of this Ordinance.</text>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.010</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <text>As used in this Ordinance, the following definitions shall apply unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>"Alcohol" shall mean neutral spirits distilled at or above 190 proof, whether or not such product is subsequently reduced for non-industrial use.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>"Alcoholic beverage" shall mean any liquid suitable for human consumption, which contains one-half of one percent or more of alcohol by volume.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>"Barter" or "Bartering" shall mean the trading for any commodity, act or consideration whether or not there is intrinsic value in the item traded.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>"Beer" shall mean any malt beverage containing more than one-half of one percent alcohol by volume.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>"Distilled spirits" shall mean any alcoholic beverage that is not beer, wine, sparkling wine or alcohol.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text>"Liquor" shall mean all varieties of liquid, semisolid, or solid substance containing alcohol, whether brewed, fermented, formulated, or distilled which is intended for human consumption.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <text>"Minor" shall mean any person under the age of twenty-one (21) years.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(h)</num>
          <text>"Possession" or "possessing" shall mean having on ones person, vehicle or other property and includes constructive possession through control without regard to ownership.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>"Purchase" shall mean the exchange, barter, traffic, receipt with or without consideration in any form.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(j)</num>
          <text>"Sale" shall mean the exchange, barter, traffic, donation, with or without consideration, in addition to the selling, supplying or distribution by any means, by any person, to any person.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(k)</num>
          <text>"Transport" shall mean the introduction of alcoholic beverage onto the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Reservation of State of New York by any means of conveyance for the purpose of sale, or distribution, to any licensed dealer.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(l)</num>
          <text>"Tribal Council" shall mean the duly elected governing body of the St. Regis Mohawk Indian Tribe of New York, a federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.020</num>
        <heading>Relation of Other Tribal Regulations</heading>
        <text>Any and all prior ordinances, resolutions, regulations or other form of control of the St. Regis Mohawk Tribe of the State of New York whether written or unwritten, which authorize, prohibit, or deal with the sale of alcohol are hereby repealed and have no further force and effect. No Tribal ordinance or regulation shall be applied in a manner inconsistent with the provisions of this ordinance.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.030</num>
        <heading>Prohibition</heading>
        <text>The introduction on the Reservation for resale, wholesale purchase, sale and dealing in liquor other than by the Tribe or an enterprise of the Tribe is prohibited. Possession of liquor on the Reservation by any person now prohibited by Federal law shall be lawful so long as possession is in conformity with this ordinance and with state law. Federal Indian Liquor laws (18 U.S.C. 1161 and 1154) shall apply to any act or transaction not authorized by this ordinance and state law and violators shall be subject to federal prosecution, as well as Tribal penalties as provided in this ordinance.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.040</num>
        <heading>Conformity with State Laws</heading>
        <text>Tribal standards for liquor transactions and possessions and consumption of liquor shall meet or exceed those required by the State of New York including but not limited to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text><u>Hours of Sale: Wine, Beer and Mixed Beverages</u>. The Tribe or an Enterprise of the Tribe may sell or offer for sale wine and beer and mixed beverages between 7 a.m. and 2 a.m. and 2 a.m. on any day except Sunday. On Sunday, the Tribe or an Enterprise of the Tribe may sell or offer for sale wine, and beer and mixed beverages between 12 noon and 2 a.m.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text><u>Hours of Consumption</u>. A person is in violation of this if he consumes or possesses with the intent to consume an alcoholic beverage in a public place on the reservation at any time on Sunday between 2 a.m. and 12 noon or on any other day between 2 a.m. and 7 a.m.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text><u>Minor</u>. A minor is <u>any</u> person who has not celebrated his/her twenty first (21) birthday.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text><u>Purchase of Alcohol by a Minor</u>. Purchase of an alcoholic beverage by a minor prohibited.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text><u>Sale to Minors</u>. Sale of an alcoholic beverage to a minor by the Tribe or an Enterprise of the Tribe is prohibited.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text><u>Consumption of Alcohol by a Minor</u>. Consumption of an alcoholic beverage by a minor is prohibited.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <text><u>Possession of Alcohol by a Minor</u>. Possession of an alcoholic beverage by a minor is prohibited unless: (1) such minor is in possession of the alcoholic beverage while in the course and scope of his employment and he is any employee of the Tribe and an Enterprise of the Tribe.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(h)</num>
          <text><u>Purchase of Alcohol for a Minor; Furnishing Alcohol to a Minor</u>. A person commits a violation of this ordinance if he knowingly purchases an alcoholic beverage for or knowingly gives or makes available an alcoholic beverage to a minor.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text><u>Misrepresentation of Age by a Minor</u>. A minor is in violation of this ordinance if he falsely states that he is 21 years of age or older or presents any document that indicates he/she is 21 years of age or older to a person engaged in selling or serving alcoholic beverages.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(j)</num>
          <text><u>Employment of Minors</u>. The Tribe or an Enterprise of the Tribe shall not employ any person under 18 years of age to sell, prepare, serve, or otherwise handle liquor, or to assist in doing so. The Tribe or an Enterprise of the Tribe may, however, employ a person under 18 years of age to work in any capacity other than the actual selling, preparing, serving or handling of liquor.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.050</num>
        <heading>Prohibition of Sales During Emergencies or Dates and Time Established by the Tribal Council</heading>
        <text>The Tribal Council Head Chief, by authority of Tribal Council resolution, may on an emergency basis and for a period of time not to exceed five (5) business days, by written order, act, directive or notice, prohibit the sale of liquor until such emergency order can be considered by the Tribal Council which may in its discretion, terminate or extend such order for any length of time it deems necessary, or may issue emergency rules, regulations directions or orders concerning the sale of liquor which will be valid during the stated emergency period. The Tribal Council may likewise issue orders prohibiting or limiting the sale of liquor for any period not to exceed seventy-two (72) consecutive hours.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.060</num>
        <heading>Sovereign Immunity Preserved</heading>
        <text>Nothing in this ordinance is intended nor shall be construed as a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the St. Regis Mohawk Tribe of the State of New York. No officer, manager or employee of an enterprise of the Tribe shall be authorized nor shall attempt to waive the sovereign immunity of the Tribe.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.070</num>
        <heading>Penalty</heading>
        <text>Any person or entity purchasing, possessing, selling, bartering, or otherwise trafficking in liquor on the reservation is in violation of this ordinance of any rule or regulation adopted pursuant to this ordinance and shall be subject to a fine or forfeiture, as applicable, of not more than Five Thousand Dollars ($5,000.00) and may be barred from admission to the Reservation through Due Process of law. In addition, persons or entities subject to the full jurisdiction of the Tribe may be subject to such other appropriate actions as the Tribal Council may determine. All contraband merchandise shall be confiscated by the Tribe and disposed of as directed by the Tribal Council.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.080</num>
        <heading>Severability</heading>
        <text>If any clause, part of section of this Ordinance shall be adjudged invalid, such judgement shall not affect or invalidate the remainder of the ordinance but shall be confined in its operation to the clause, part or section directly involved in controversy in which such judgement was rendered.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.090</num>
        <heading>Disclaimer</heading>
        <text>Nothing in this ordinance shall be construed to authorize or require the criminal trial and punishment of non-Indians by the St. Regis Mohawk Tribe of the State of New York except to the extent allowed by an applicable present or future Act of Congress or any applicable laws.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.100</num>
        <heading>Regulations</heading>
        <text>The Tribal Council shall have the authority to adopt and enforce rules and regulations to implement this ordinance and to further the purposes thereof.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.110</num>
        <heading>Enforcement</heading>
        <text>This ordinance shall be enforced by the Tribal Council, or any other Agency vested with such enforcement authority by resolution of the Tribal Council.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.120</num>
        <heading>Effective Date</heading>
        <text>This ordinance shall be effective upon the date that the Secretary of the Interior certifies this ordinance and published in the Federal Register.</text>
      </section>
      <section>
        <num>4.04.130</num>
        <heading>Duration</heading>
        <text>The Duration of This Ordinance Shall Be Perpetual</text>
      </section>
    </container>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>4.06</num>
    <heading>Petroleum Fuel Ordinance</heading>
  </container>
</container>