<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<container xmlns="https://open.law/schemas/library" xmlns:citations="https://open.law/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://open.law/schemas/macro" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns:codified="https://open.law/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://open.law/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="Saint Regis Mohawk Tribal Code of Law">
  <prefix>Title</prefix>
  <num>8</num>
  <heading>Enrollment and Membership</heading>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>8.01</num>
    <heading>Membership Ordinance</heading>
    <text class="center">
      <strong>Preamble</strong>
    </text>
    <text>We the people of The Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe do hereby enact this Membership Code in order to avoid sex discrimination; provide criteria for membership for children; provide criteria for membership for spouses; and, to provide for applications for membership and appeals of determinations by the Tribal clerk.</text>
    <text>The purpose for the Code is to ensure the ongoing strength of the people of The Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe; to provide fair and just criteria for eligibility; and, to provide notice concerning eligibility requirements.</text>
    <text>People presently enrolled as members on the Tribal Roll will not be removed as a result of the enactment of this Code.</text>
    <text>Applications for membership are to be made through the Tribal Clerk; should someone disagree with the Tribal Clerk, then provisions are made for appeal to a Membership Court. All will be done in a timely manner.</text>
    <annotations>
      <annotation type="Commentary">Note that since the Tribal Council’s adoption of the 1986 Membership Code subsequent Tribal Council Resolutions have been adopted to address any inconsistencies and ambiguities that have arisen over the years. See <cite doc="Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe Res. No. 2003-203">TCR 2003-203</cite>, <cite doc="Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe Res. No. 2005-90">TCR 2005-90</cite> and <cite doc="Saint Regis Mohawk Tribe Res. No. 2007-63">TCR 2007-63</cite>.</annotation>
    </annotations>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
    <num>8.04</num>
    <heading>Tribal Residency Ordinance</heading>
  </container>
</container>
